<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2024-05-11T22:00:21-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">el766@cornell.edu</title><subtitle>Ertai Liu's personal website</subtitle><author><name>Ertai Liu</name></author><entry><title type="html">Robotics Summit &amp;amp; Expo recap</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/Robotics-Summit-&-Expo/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Robotics Summit &amp;amp; Expo recap" /><published>2024-05-11T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2024-05-11T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/Robotics%20Summit%20&amp;%20Expo</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/Robotics-Summit-&amp;-Expo/">&lt;p&gt;May 11th, 2024&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Several days ago, I had the pleasure of introducing our latest agricultural robotic innovation at the Form and Function Challenge during the Robotic Summit &amp;amp; Expo in Boston! Our new design prioritizes cost and energy efficiency while enhancing performance in navigating narrow and rugged agricultural terrain, particularly in vineyards. Using this concept, we constructed a compact 3D printed model car and were thrilled to witness its seamless execution of zero-point turns and Ackermann-like steering across diverse environments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The whole competition was very joyful, and we received much more than we expected. There are visotors stoping by our booths throughout the time, engaging with our presentation and offering invaluable suggestions. We forged connections with robotic component suppliers, like-minded companies, patent lawyers, and journalists, receiving insightful feedback on both our robotic design and business strategies. Additionally, we relished the opportunity of enjoying the exhibitions of the Robotics Summit &amp;amp; Expo, all at no cost!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is one technical lesson that we learned though. We wanted our small robot car to traverse in a rectangular patter on the booth by tracking the AprilTag. However we found that the motion blur of camera images made the tracking very unstable, partially due to the change of ambient light in the exhibition hall. Ideally we could have changed the tag patterns to a simpler, less informative but more robust one to overcome this issue, but unfortunately we were too late to find out this problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have a robotic idea that you want to try out, I would definately encourage you to apply. The application is very easy. It is just a google form describing briefly about what’s the purpose and the design concept of your robot. You will hear back from them within several days after the application deadline. You do need to specify how you would like to use the components from sponsors. This competition has sponsors from almost all aspects of robotics and they are all very easy to reach out and they are committed to help you!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve also put together a short video capturing our experience at the event and our project. Should you wish to learn more about our journey or express interest in our robot, please don’t hesitate to reach out. We’re eager to share our experiences and insights with you!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- Courtesy of embedresponsively.com --&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;responsive-video-container&quot;&gt;
    &lt;iframe src=&quot;https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/PyDf2UOSq90&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; webkitallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; mozallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name>Ertai Liu</name></author><summary type="html">May 11th, 2024</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">IROS2023 Presentation</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/IROS2023/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="IROS2023 Presentation" /><published>2023-10-05T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2023-10-05T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/IROS2023</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/IROS2023/">&lt;p&gt;October 5th, 2023&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am delighted to share that our research on visual navigation with automatic annotation has been accepted and presented at the IROS2023 conference in Detroit! I am sincerely grateful for the thoughtful questions and insightful comments I received both during and after the conference. If you have any interest in discussing this project or any of my other endeavors, please don’t hesitate to reach out—I’m more than happy to engage in conversation!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/Posts/2023_10_05.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Ertai Liu</name></author><summary type="html">October 5th, 2023</summary></entry></feed>